<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-29T14:51:26-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ryan Remaly</title><subtitle>An amazing website.</subtitle><author><name>Ryan Remaly</name></author><entry><title type="html">A Happy Accident</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/A-Happy-Accident/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Happy Accident" /><published>2020-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/A-Happy-Accident</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/A-Happy-Accident/">&lt;p&gt;Life sometimes has the ability to throw a few curveballs, especially when things seem to settle down. On a cold morning in February 2019 I was doing what I had done for the last 6 months. Drive to work. Only this morning was a little different because there was more ice on the road than normal. I’m sure you know where this is headed so I’ll save the colorful language and just say I wrecked my 2003 Honda Accord into a white composite fence after taking too sharp a turn. This was the first accident (and hopefully the last) I’d ever had and I was just a bit shocked at first. Shock was very quicky overtaken by a weird mix of anger and sadness. After writing a note and leaving it in the mailbox a lady ended up walking out from the home that sat behind the fence and offered me to come in while the police came. She assured me that this particular event was an annual occurence; I was just the lucky contenstant this year. The cop gave me a ticket for failure to control and my car was towed with pieces dragging behind. But why would I be telling you this? Because it was one of the better mistakes I’ve made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to also fill you in on someting before I go deeper into this story. Before this accident occurred, I could’t tell you the difference between an alternator and a carburetor or a carburetor from a radiator. After my car got dropped off on the driveway I taped up some of the bumper and drove it over to Grismer. They quoted me $2400 in damage; considering the car was probably worth around that much I knew I was either going to have to do what was easy (buy a new car) or start getting creative. I thanked them for the diagnostic, took my keys and drove home to start the fun part. The first thing I did was look up junkyards around me to see if they have some of the parts needed to frankenstein my vehicle back together. Turns out the internet has changed the junking game because the pick and pull in Columbus had catalogued inventory of all the vehicles on the premises. They had 4 of the same color ‘03 Honda Accord’s that I had so I drove up an hour from Dayton to take a look. I needed a bumper, a front left headlight, a new air intake box, and a drivers side door in addition to new brake pads, rotors and calipers (hindsight now tells me that I probably only needed new pads but mechanics are always trying to make another buck off ya). I pulled out of the lot with a new looking drivers door, headlight, and air intake box for around 55 bucks. The only thing I didn’t end up with was the bumper. Turns out amazon had a black bumper for 80 bucks and I ordered pads, rotors, and calipers from Ebay for a little over 100. Probably wouldn’t order the brakes off ebay again but they have worked well for me after almost 2 years so it can’t be that bad. What followed was a 7 seven day battle of me vs the car. I’d come from work and work until I was ready for bed. Along the way I had to buy many new gadgets aquired from a mix of harbor freight, lowes, and craigslist. All in all I spent around $600 bucks, only a quarter what the mechanic was asking and I scored many socket wrenches and bits, 2 air impact drills, an air compressor, 2 jack stands, a torque wrench, and a hydraulic car jack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all this experince made me much more comfortable around my car and I look forward to it breaking down. Earlier this year I busted my window out picking up wood to build a standing desk. I ended up going to the same Columbus pick and pull and picking out a passenger rear window for 20 bucks. The tint is a little different but it doesnt look so bad. I also have done 3 oil changes since then the first taking a little over an hour from start to finish, the second around 45 minutes, and the last maybe half an hour or so. Iteration is important. I’m eyeballing the 200,000 mile mark, only 10,000 miles away, to begin my next test, replacing the timing belt. I’ve put a few pictures of my car when it was stripped down and the busted window below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/MKTga850LvPDPinmBc50maRlrSC5yH7CHhXixfRGx3obWalAqKGrdDNbrJYn_0eeyLLjNKI3168ukNBAgz8dBeCRrUSe-CepyiVznJA24UoCUQPyT0pvO3S0WJjqmKlvNwbpzOB2=w300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/hUDr32tFw_L8jh_K_lZ-0bhWUwoGSGzu63jeh9T2zMLF6lGbyYmgOA6p9J-B95UukMSovi1Dtg05igRpzRaq8ShKN59JF-V_v9Oy_KyyrbWoH6yo8ofCkdAMwHY0JQQ8mnU5Mw8p=w300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/xKQagRRz8yUDJhsYYV6VF-vEuWpGZ8MKpxJCvtNEYkNCUBuZCcnqfEK1JQ92jiEECqt_0gVMYYOIYRtkQz8nts03cO7elS0CuDiQukTMUX5kKlfoswIlOuXxhdYMrE0iOl4rnQUneQ=w300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/LKMzHnZ2BB6aCtzCVcW-ybkb9YYVNG6sVHxQ4fC9ycma_k50GVjdsOsTyOMhhWoUdlAGFAfk9uJxIleQJG7LZniYSAxgkSxGMob_KgWZEGu7vL3End8BTRYMetIBDPPP9bI5p0V8=w300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onward and Upward&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ryan</name></author><summary type="html">Life sometimes has the ability to throw a few curveballs, especially when things seem to settle down. On a cold morning in February 2019 I was doing what I had done for the last 6 months. Drive to work. Only this morning was a little different because there was more ice on the road than normal. I’m sure you know where this is headed so I’ll save the colorful language and just say I wrecked my 2003 Honda Accord into a white composite fence after taking too sharp a turn. This was the first accident (and hopefully the last) I’d ever had and I was just a bit shocked at first. Shock was very quicky overtaken by a weird mix of anger and sadness. After writing a note and leaving it in the mailbox a lady ended up walking out from the home that sat behind the fence and offered me to come in while the police came. She assured me that this particular event was an annual occurence; I was just the lucky contenstant this year. The cop gave me a ticket for failure to control and my car was towed with pieces dragging behind. But why would I be telling you this? Because it was one of the better mistakes I’ve made.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My iPad Experience</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/MyiPadExperience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My iPad Experience" /><published>2020-11-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/MyiPadExperience</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/MyiPadExperience/">&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2020, I purchased a 12.9 inch iPad pro after discovering the feature sidecar. For those unfamiliar, sidecar allows you to use your iPad as a second monitor for your macbook with or without a wire. Considering the amount of developement I had been doing on Global Gaming with my 13in macbook I was already in the market for a monitor. While the price of the 12.9 pad deterred me initially, the flexibility it offered ultimately proved to be the selling point. The ability to have a duel monitor setup wherever and whenever seemed too good to be true. For some things I am willing to cough up the cash and this was one of those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After around 4 months of use I can safely say the iPad is the best device I have ever owned and will only get better with age. I used to keep notes in journals, then I kept notes on index cards in a plastic box, but the iPad has nullifed both of those things, and I’m better off for it. Now I’m not going to say that paper and pen does not have a purpose because it clearly does but what the iPad offers is just &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt;. It has become a personal repository of past work, thoughts, and everything in between. But like many things in life, what you get out of it is directly attributed to what you put into it. At this point it is clear to me that this thing will not find its grave in an old desk drawer anytime soon, as it has now become part of my everyday routine. While I do believe it is bizarre to have so much of my daily routine connected to a piece of metal, I guess sometimes you just have to accept things for what they are. If it improves your life and feels right then whats the harm?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And before any of you claim that I am an Apple Sheep who buys all of the latest and greatest devices because it makes me feel superior to the other apple-less peasants, go ahead and take a look at my cell phone below. When I get tired of not being able to easily read text I will go on eBay and purchase another original iPhone SE for $50, and will continue to do so until Apple stops supporting it with updates. Hopefully by that time the new iPhone 12 mini will be under $300.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that seems like a good enough rant for now. Here’s a few pictures I’ve made with procreate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/eWNEpzTRzFRlg5rZokafTO6v5WajKJaXJe0kK5h6tQV6HhCo2Kq9rA-ULjml59IiJuzBU8M8BlxhylNREgNSvJWJp0MWwye-0ZXd_benZ37ZM4jLE_UxoJ09Sa3N-aVgm6SdFzG4=w300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/4ewl5I63ddw6obBBMAPB6v9b0GnkDsA3ScHMfTU_WMj37L7FnK1ujoxtycijKTmsohBuiSSMX6xHw-laHMM2gd9VmscZh89xnv7PhIX6Syr4qef2oGu6KRtKYpDMekNzZwBnxens=w300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/l411T2F8SAKX9tathC-8xX0votgPfconEWnix7MuyNvEBOfeRHkWsRBMvelgtpVzidyqDokc6PCsbC_o_rQC3iKFVMUTa2gNsEXGpgoD5Q6KMNtNpTWj19LJmjvxlrcT0_aRaoJL=w300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/4cYfavsGQQWSk1jBfwYMii9MrfBaT2uIRtvSZ_0xOj0jeli1ZDjIbn-xpzj4L6TWBNk6XwpdqZLjXZBJLJdSr5o9roVy0KsXvTevVqgmdrXgTPFw6fXUkkfMPc523faB2F5LDuH4=w300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/lg_MPpguf8w9yEGgDkVSXt8NWOVgmqmU9ihbBWRKl1vwalfOsAaz_EjunbLZz9KR7r9tDiITLa0HgMaj5LsqtOoVy8gN3UnjalAQYiNkzCvIAF3IT-A8DrbnT9WlKlp-7-gK2Bgg=w300&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/mBfSm0LVqPu7lID3qT6U9Z8nJdzQn3nb6zxGsqqbQtJXcu86r4S2XdQO_upYwLxIsjfwPJ4ty0bFaLzVdWbmoJSYGN_lvsZg5rl1nBs_dRU737GME98kTrfcg_Y354rmKg_3AB4u=w300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onward and Upward.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ryan</name></author><summary type="html">In the summer of 2020, I purchased a 12.9 inch iPad pro after discovering the feature sidecar. For those unfamiliar, sidecar allows you to use your iPad as a second monitor for your macbook with or without a wire. Considering the amount of developement I had been doing on Global Gaming with my 13in macbook I was already in the market for a monitor. While the price of the 12.9 pad deterred me initially, the flexibility it offered ultimately proved to be the selling point. The ability to have a duel monitor setup wherever and whenever seemed too good to be true. For some things I am willing to cough up the cash and this was one of those things.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/firstPost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World" /><published>2020-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/firstPost</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/firstPost/">&lt;p&gt;Hello whoever is reading this. I realistically should have done this many years ago but you know what they say about planting a tree. If I said I had a complete vision for how this blog/portfolio would end up I’d be lying. I figure if I’m working on something I feel passionate about or think is interesting I’ll post about it here. Well I suppose thats all I got for now. Thanks for stopping by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onward and Upward&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ryan</name></author><summary type="html">Hello whoever is reading this. I realistically should have done this many years ago but you know what they say about planting a tree. If I said I had a complete vision for how this blog/portfolio would end up I’d be lying. I figure if I’m working on something I feel passionate about or think is interesting I’ll post about it here. Well I suppose thats all I got for now. Thanks for stopping by.</summary></entry></feed>